杰森:[低声]噢耶!赶快过来啊!孩子们!
Jason: Yea [Grunts] Come on baby.
迈克:嗨,嗨!嗨嗨!!
Mike: Hello?Hello?Aloha?Whoa.
(笑声)
(Laughter)
开萝尔:果不出我所料,这次渡假差劲之极!
Carol: I said it before and I'll say it again, this whole vacation stinks!
杰森:开萝尔,如果不能说点好听的,那就请你免开尊口!
Jason: Carol if you can't say something positive, don't say anything at all.
开萝尔:当我没说!
Carol: Fine!
迈克:这样她就不会唠叨个没完了?
Mike: That's all it takes to shut her up?
妈妈:迈克,你也是!
Mom: That applies to you to Mike.
今天真是倒霉透顶,这条破船停在这里动也动不了,
Things are bad enough with us stuck on this rundown garbage scout with
通讯也中断了,该怎么办呀!
a broken motor and a radio that probably never worked.
杰森:行了!麦琪,你的话真够鼓舞人心!
Jason: Well, thanks for those positive words Maggie.
妈妈:最近手头是有点紧,所以你就租了条船不像船的破玩意,
Mom: Oh did I say anything about the false economy of renting this thing
我都没说你什么,你还想怎么样?!
instead of a real boat just to save a few measly dollars?
杰森:一共省下了175美元,这还不够?再说,这破玩意怎么也是只船!
Jason: Well, that was $175 measly dollars and this thing is a boat.
麦琪:连个洗手间都没有,不是破玩意是什么?
Maggie: If it doesn't have a bathroom it's not a real boat.
本:我们会困死在这吗?
Ben: Are we gonna die?
妈妈:乖孩子,当然不会!
Mom: No, honey we are not going to die.
迈克:不会!困在这个四面漏水的破玩意上,
Mike: No, we're just stranded on a leaky boat somewhere off the coast
谁也联系不上;我们还会遇上别的危险吗?
of maui without any way to communicate.What do we have to worry about?
开萝尔:鲨鱼!!
Carol: Sharks.
本:真的?!
Ben: Really?!
杰森:开萝尔,别信口开河吓着你弟弟了.
Jason: Carol, don't frighten your brother.
本:我又不是胆小鬼,怕什么!
Ben: I'm not scared, Dad, sharks are neat!
老爸,
This is the first good news I've had since we've been on this rundown
鲨鱼没你说得那么可怕!上了这条破船后最让人开心的莫过于此了.
old garbage scout.
(笑声)
(Laughter)
杰森:别担心,
Jason: Now come on, the coast guards gonna find us.
海岸警卫队会找到我们的.
Let's look at this as the Seaver clan's great adventure.
趁此良机我们还是把它当作一次伟大探险来享受吧.这是全家人第一次一起乘船来到太平洋中的毛利岛上共度美好时光,
You realize this is the first time since we got to Maui that we've had
我们得好好珍惜才行!!
the chance to spend some real time together?This is a family vacation, right?
开萝尔:拉倒吧!【看着麦琪】对不起!
Carol: Oh, please.[Looks at Maggie] Sorry!
爸爸:我有个好主意!现在,让我们举行家庭赛歌会!我来开头!
Dad: I know what this group needs!Time for the Seaver song fest!Come on.
【唱歌】划啊划!划啊划!我们的船坏了!该你了,麦琪!
[singing] Row row row your boat gently down...take it Maggie!
麦琪:你唱你的吧!
Maggie: I don't feel like taking it.
杰森:孩子们接着唱!【继续唱歌】划啊划!划啊划!我们的船坏了!高兴点啊!【歌声渐弱】
Jason: Everybody else then![Continues singing] Row row row your boat gently down the stream, merrily, merrily [fades off]
杰森:【语无伦次地乱唱一气】一起来唱!
Jason: [Singing incoherently] Everybody sing!
统统给我收声!!
Everybody: Stop!
杰森:听你的!
Jason: Ok.
本:妈妈!爸爸!还有番茄酱没?
Ben: Mom!Dad!Do we have any ketchup left?
麦琪:孩子,不是刚刚吃过午饭吗?
Maggie: Lunch is over, Ben.
本:不是我吃,红色的番茄酱很像血,
Ben: It's not for me; it's for Jaws.
所以我想鲨鱼也会把它当成血的.
I'm gonna fool him into thinking it's blood.
迈克:笨蛋!
Mike: Ben, that is so stupid.
本:我是笨蛋?那你呢?记得有一次上学时,我全身涂满了番茄酱,结果把莫妮卡·布鲁克给吓得半死,莫妮卡再笨也笨不过鲨鱼吧?!
Ben: Oh, yea?Well, when I poured ketchup all over my shirt at school Monica
Brooker would scream and she's a lot smarter than some dumb fish
杰森:番茄酱给你,孩子!
Jason: Here you go, Ben.Happy hunting.
但愿你能把鲨鱼骗倒.我们做点什么好呢?
All right everybody, what will we do next?
开萝尔:我憋不住了,想吐!
Carol: May I throw up, please?
本:快来啊,鲨鱼!我这有你最喜欢的鲜血,快来啊!
Ben: Here sharky, sharky.Here's blood for you.
杰森:怎么回事?
Jason: What's the matter with you people?
在家时大家不都愿意来毛利岛的吗,
I mean we're in paradise here, together.
可到了这天堂般的地方,反而没了笑脸,
What about the smiling faces you all had when we sat around the living
究竟怎么了?
room and we voted unanimously to come to Maui?
杰森:不会又想去佛罗里达了吧?
Jason: So what's it gonna be folks?Florida or...
本:毛利!毛利!
Ben: Maui!Maui!
开萝尔和本:毛利!毛利!毛利!!
Carol and Ben: Maui!Maui!Maui!
麦琪和迈克:毛利!毛利!!
Maggie and Mike: Maui!Maui!
大家一起【呼喊】:毛利!毛利!!!
Everybody: [Chanting] Maui!
迈克:毛利万岁!!
Mike: Maui would be ok!
麦琪:毛利万岁!
Maggie: Oh, Maui!
杰森:现在,我们又团结在一起了!
Jason: Well, it's unanimous then!
麦琪:只要我们聚在一起,什么都好说!
Maggie: As long as we're all together!
开萝尔:应该让爸爸也知道.
Carol: We should just tell him.
麦琪:开萝尔,什么都别说!
Maggie: Carol, be quiet.
杰森:麦琪你想跟我说什么?
Jason: Tell me what?
麦琪:杰森,
Maggie: Honey, the truth is,
其实孩子们和我都不太愿意来这渡假.
is that none of us was really that excited about coming here.
杰森:你说什么?
Jason: What?
开萝尔:我们打心眼里不愿来这浪费时间.
Carol: We despise the idea in the very marrow of our bones.
迈克:我完全支持爸爸来这玩!
Mike: Oh, no not me.I was totally stoked.
开萝尔:得了吧!当初爸爸提出来这渡假你是怎么说来着?
Carol: Not at first.Remember when we first heard about this trip?
杰森:原来如此!既然我们一家人聚在一块,我想我们可以重新决定要去哪里!
Jason: Alright, now that we're all together, I guess we can begin.
开萝尔:真的?
Carol: What?
杰森:现在西维尔一家要开家庭会议,人人都得参加,
Jason: It's time for another Seaver family meeting and none of you is
谁也不准缺席.
going anywhere!
开萝尔:可是,鲍比一会就过来,那该怎么办?
Carol: But Bobby's going to be here in less than an hour.
杰森:邀请他过来玩,这事你也没事先告诉我们?
Jason: So you had him coming over before you asked us?
开萝尔:我们还是先开西维尔家庭会议吧?!
Carol: I move that the Seaver family meeting be called to order.
杰森:算你机灵!
Jason: Smart girl, so moved.
麦琪:那就开始吧!
Maggie: I second that.
杰森:谁有意见就快点.
Jason: All right, anyone have any old business to discuss?
迈克:能不能过几天再说.
Mike: I do.I hereby move that we adjourn this meeting.
杰森:不行!家庭会议由我主持.
Jason: You're out of order.Chair hereby recognizes himself.
本:你是老爸,当然得你主持了.
Ben: Yep, that's you all right!
杰森:那好,
Jason: Well, I'd like to give you the preliminary report of the summer
下面由我代表夏令活动小组向大家作报告.
activities subcommittee.
迈克:不会吧?
Mike: What?
爸爸:针对西维尔一家的具体情况,我拟定了两组方案供大家讨论.
Dad; I come before you with two proposals for the Seaver family
本:太好了!!
Ben: Great!
开萝尔:渡假?!
Carol: What vacation?!
杰森:你妈妈忙工作的时候,
Jason: Well, you said to handle this because you were too busy with the
这些事便交给我全权负责.
paper and boy, did I handle it.
麦琪:嗯……
Maggie: Well, I, uh...
本:那我们到底要去哪里?
Ben: Where we going?!
杰森:说道点子上了,小家伙!我们西维尔一家紧密团结在一块,是吧?
Jason: That's the spirit, Ben!Yes!The Seaver family together, right?
本:嗯,没错!
Ben: Right!
杰森:嗯…是去迪斯尼乐园痛痛快快地玩上十天?
Jason: Ok, what will it be, ten fun-filled days at Disneyworld?
本:好!好!好!
Ben: Yea, yea, yea!
杰森:还是在毛利岛舒舒服服地过上十天?【沉默】看把你们给吓得!
Jason: Or ten days in Maui?[Silence] Takes your breath away, doesn't it?
对此今晚的家庭会议一定要作出决定.
Alright, so basically that's what we have to vote on tonight.
迈克:爸爸,你办公室的电话在响.
Mike: Dad, your office phone is ringing.
杰森:大家先讨论讨论再说.
Jason: Ok, well, you just, uh, talk among yourselves.
这十天是要去毛利岛呢还是去佛罗里达奥兰多?
What will it be, ten days in Maui or ten days in Orlando, Florida?
最好是选择花费最低的地方,不过大家也不必过分在意这一点.
Which by the way is the least expensive of the two.
最重要的是我们一家人要在一起,
Not that that should be a factor in your decision.
一家人在一起就行!
Just as long as we're all together, as long as.
本:爸爸,有精神病患者找你!
Ben: Dad, your mental patient.
杰森:我知道,我们先讨论这事.
Jason: Right, just, uh, talk.
【随即大家开始了讨论】
[Everybody starts talking at once]
开萝尔:嗯,妈妈,我很想去,但是…
Carol: Aw, Mom I'd love to go, but...
妈妈:就此打住!
Mom: Shhh...
【迈克和开萝尔同时说话】
[Mike and Carol at the same time]
迈克:妈妈.我打算跟埃迪和波纳一起出去玩个十天半月.钓鱼啦,露营啦,我们一起去闹一起去玩,您看怎么样?妈妈,我都十七岁了,正是玩的时候,您就让我去吧??
Mike: Comon Mom.I was planning on hanging out with Eddie and Boner in the pokemons for a week or two.Go camping and fishing, some good clean fun.Mom?I mean, I'm 17, I should have fun while I'm young, shouldn't I?
开萝尔:【吞吞吐吐地说】七月份,鲍比不用上班,他休息在家.所以我不想出去了,同时也省点钱,妈您看成吗?
Carol: [incoherent] July is the one month that Bobby isn't going to be working.I know, Mom, save your money by not going, how's that?
本:哇塞!他们两个都不去,这下可好了!
Ben: Wow!This vacation's gonna be neat!
麦琪:乖儿子,你能不能把点心带出去坐在沙发上边看电视边吃?
Maggie: Oh, honey Ben.
Would you mind taking your dessert into the living room and watching a
little television?
本:那我去了!
Ben: Sure!
迈克和开萝尔:老妈!!
Mike and Carol: Aw, Mom!
麦琪:你们俩能不能替你爸爸和我多想想.
Maggie: You two could have a little consideration for someone else's feelings.
开萝尔:可是…..
Carol: But I...
麦琪:如果此次渡假难以成行,
Maggie: If this vacation doesn't happen,
他会一天到晚闹个不停.
he'll be moping around the house and crying for a month.
迈克:他现在都11岁了,我想说说就没问题了.
Mike: He'll get over it.He's 11.
麦琪:不是你弟弟,是你爸爸.他今年已经39岁了!
Maggie: No, he's not.He's 39.
迈克:那像我这么大的时候,
Mike: When you were my age,
你是不是也愿意跟父母一起出去玩上十几天?
did you want to go off with your parents for 10 days?
麦琪:那当然…不过,老实说…
Maggie: I most certainly...Well, honestly, I...
开萝尔:老妈…
Carol: Mom...
麦琪:我也不明白你爸为什么非要在今年去毛利岛渡假?
Maggie: Oh why did you father have to pick this year of all years for
a wonderful, beautiful, romantic vacation like Maui?
迈克:嗯,我们还是去告诉他我们实在不能和他一起去.
Mike: Well, I guess we'll just have to tell him that we can't go.
麦琪:不能这样.
Carol: No.Let's make this decision in the right spirit.Let's vote for Florida.
还是选择去佛罗里达吧!这样既省了钱让你爸爸高兴,
It'll make your father happy because it's cheaper,
又能让你弟弟高兴,
it'll make little Ben happy,
同时距离也近,有什么事也好赶回来.
and it's only a two-hour flight if any of us happen to have to rush
你们俩瞧着行不行?
back to see our editors.Agreed?
开萝尔:同意!
Carol: Sure.
迈克:嗯,可以!
Mike: I guess.
麦琪:但谁也不许向你爸爸提起此事.
Maggie: And we won't mention a word of this to your father.
开萝尔:那我该不该告诉鲍比呢?
Carol: How am I going to break the news to Bobby, huh?
迈克:那我寻开心呢吧!这倒好,
Mike: What are you kidding me?
鲍比有机会独个儿痛快地玩几天了.而我们却得去10日游,
This trip will give him a chance to do a little trolling.
真没劲!这个是,
Alright, well, ten days with tinker bell or we've got...Holy Toledo!
好家伙,圣托里岛,看见美女了没,
Look at this babe.Oh and this one!Ai yai yai!
美若天仙!啊呀,
This is an island full of foxes here!Wait a minute.
原来这里盛产美女,我怎么从不知道毛利岛在夏威夷呢?
Why didn't someone tell me this, this Maui place is Hawaii?
开萝尔:就你!
Carol: And that's when Mike went to work.
迈克:我怎么了!现在老哥我有要事要办.
Mike: I sure did.And I started with the weakest link.
本:大哥!
Ben: Hey!
迈克:班尼,班尼!
Mike: Benny, Benny, my lad.We must talk.
大哥有事想跟你说说,老实说,难道你真的愿意在那个无聊透顶的佛罗里达呆上十天?
Alright now, do you really want to spend 10 boring days in Orlando, Florida?
本:迪斯尼乐园无聊透顶?你没开玩笑吧?
Ben: At Disney World?Are you kidding?
迈克:那你瞧瞧这是什么?
Mike: Alright, just look at this.
本:这个?那不是身戴椰子的女孩吗.
Ben: So?It's a girl with coconuts on her...
迈克:观察力不错嘛!
Mike: Exactly.
本:哇塞!在毛利岛竟然还可以骑马!
Ben: Wow!This Maui has horseback riding!
迈克:哪来的马?老弟,瞧仔细没?我看你是青春期到了.这女孩她……
Mike: Horses?Ben, let me remind you, you're in puberty now.Now girls are...
本:看见她们我就想在海边纵马驰骋!
Ben: They let you ride on the beach!
迈克:老弟,你不能……呃,
Mike: Ben, you're not gonna...I mean, uh, yea, yea.
其实我是说你想干什么都行,
Yea, dude, you can just ride your little brains out over there.
即便是在海滩上骑马,
And I wouldn't be surprised if they let you keep your horse right in your
即使你把马骑进旅馆房间那也没什么大不了的,只要你喜欢就行!!
hotel room!
本:一言为定!
Ben: Alright!
开萝尔:不行!我可不想和男朋友相隔6000英里.
Carol: No!I am not going to be 6,000 miles from the man I love.
迈克:是不是,呆在佛罗里达就好些呢?
Mike: So what, 1,200 miles to Florida is better?
开萝尔:那当然!那样的话,我们至少在同一个时区内.
Carol: Yes!At least we'll be in the same time zone.
迈克:噢,原来如此!
Mike: Why?So you can call him every hour and make sure he's not out scamming
这样你就可以时时跟他联络了,这样他就不会跟其他女孩子混在一起了?
babes?Ah ha!That's it!That's it!
开萝尔:你的废话就是多,我看你还是闭嘴的好.
Carol: I'm gonna put goofy glue in your zit cream.
迈克:如果我能使爸妈准许你呆在家里,
Mike: What would you do for me if I promised to get Mom and Dad to
你能给我什么好处?
let you stay home?
开萝尔:真的?
Carol: What?!
迈克:主意我倒是有,你想听听吗?
Mike: I had her hooked then.So you're interested?
开萝尔:大哥,如果让我选择去毛利岛,那我宁愿不去的好.
Carol: Mike said if I voted for Maui, I wouldn't have to go.
男友:我休息的时候你要花十天去渡假?
Boyfriend: Ten days in July?Oh, Carol, that's when my summer job ends.
我想我们应该在开学前多花点时间在一起!
We were supposed to spend some time together before school starts.
开萝尔:听着,好消息是,
Carol: No, wait!You haven't heard the good news.
我哥他说有办法能让我留在家中!
Mike has promised to fix it so I don't have to go with them!
男友:那好!
Boyfriend: Alright!
开萝尔:不用担心,我会呆在这里陪你的.
Carol: So, for ten days I'll be here, all alone.
爸爸,家庭会议的决定出炉了!
So you see, Dad, the family vote was rigged.
杰森:到底要去哪里,佛罗里达,还是……
Jason: So what will it be then, folks?Florida or...
本:毛利岛!毛利岛!毛利岛!!
Ben: Maui!Maui!Maui!
麦琪:毛利岛?
Maggie: Maui?
迈克:毛利岛一定很好玩,是吧,老妹?
Mike: Maui would be ok, right Carol?
开萝尔:嗯,没错,毛利岛肯定很好玩!!
Carol: Yes, Maui!
杰森:看来我们达成一致了.
Jason: Well, then it's unanimous.
麦琪:只要家人能聚在一起,怎么都行.
Maggie: As long as we're all together.
杰森:我也这么认为.
Jason: Oh.
麦琪:亲爱的,我……
Maggie: Honey, I...
杰森:我知道你想说什么!不过,
Jason: No, no, no.It's fine.Hey, it's fine.Yep, it's just fine.
我觉得这个注意也很不错.起码大家都能过得很愉快,我也很想在大海里畅游!
Well, I will have a good time for all of you because I'm going swimming.
本:爸爸,爸爸,爸爸!鲨鱼来了!!
Ben: Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy!A shark!
麦琪:杰森!杰森!快游过来!!
Maggie: Jason!Jason!Swim back here!
迈克:老爸!快点游过来啊!!快点!!!
Mike: Dad!Come on!Swim!
开萝尔:快点!快点啊!!
Carol: Hurry!Hurry!
本:鲨鱼向你游过去了!!快点逃啊!!
Ben: And Jaws is closing in.Run for your life it's Jaws!
迈克:嗨!老弟,那根本就不是鲨鱼,鲨鱼怎么会喷水呢!
Mike: Ben, Ben.That's not a shark.Sharks do not have blowholes.
本:只要它们愿意,它们想怎么都行!!
Ben: They can if they want to.
杰森:我刚才跳进海里为什么来着?
Jason: And where was I before all the commotion?
还不是让大家高兴高兴.除了游泳还有钓鱼,
Oh, that's right, I was having fun for everybody.I was swimming.
钓鱼可比游泳有趣得多!!
You know, fishing is fun, too.Fishing is more fun than swimming.
开萝尔:都是你的馊主意!!
Carol: This whole mess is all your fault, you know.
迈克:都是我的错?你以为我愿意困在这个鬼地方?我本想跟,嗯,跟,呃,跟死党去泡妞!
Mike: Mine?Look, you think I like being stuck out here?Man, I have got
to get back to, uh, I've got to, uh, um.Let's just say I've got
a little rendezvous, alright
开萝尔:泡妞?你会拼泡妞这个词吗?
Carol: Rendezvous?Spell it.
迈克:R-u-n,算你狠,
Mike: R-u-n...alright, so I can't spell it.Big deal.
我不会拼又能怎么样,
But Mike Seaver does not limit what he does to what he can spell.
但迈克·西维尔想做的事不一定非得拼出来不可.
And speaking of doing,
来这个鬼地方,让我错过了不少找乐子的好机会.
ever since we got here a whole world has been going on you've missed.
杰森:哇噢!都瞧瞧这是什么!!
Jason: Whoa-ho!Will you look at this view?
我说过这里是天堂,没错吧?
Didn't I tell you guys we'd be in paradise?
迈克:出发之前,我就在想,
Mike: I was trying to figure out how many nights we were going to have
到了毛利岛我能碰上多少美女,看到她们我又该说些什么.嘿,
in Maui and how many women I'd get a chance to meet.When I saw her.
这个美女是谁,怎么刚来就看到了她!!
Who was this fox?How come I saw her the minute we got to Maui?
杰森:迈克,正经点!!
Jason: Hey, Mike!
迈克:她的旅行团竟然和我们住在同一家旅馆?!真是太好了,
Mike: And how was it possible that her tour group was staying at our hotel?
上帝把她当作我在夏威夷的初体验赐给我,
It was so clear to me.
好像遇不到她就是违背上帝意旨的罪恶,
God was telling me that this girl should be my first Hawaiian experience.
感谢上帝,我会遵从您的意旨.
Like if I didn't at least try to meet her it would be a bad sin.
杰森:迈克,行了!
Jason: Mike, come on!
迈克:爸爸你知道我总是喜欢作正确的事情,总是愿意服从上帝的安排!!
Mike: You know I always like to do the right thing.
(唱歌)
(sing)
本地导游:嗨,为什么我们不拉近点距离呢?嗯,你好像还没付钱就参加我们的旅行团!?
Local tour guide: Ok, why don't we just get a little bit closer together?Ok, that's it.Looks like someone's just joined my tour without paying.
迈克:嘿,别这么小气行不行?
Mike: Hey, how'd you spot me?
本地导游:啊哦!你能不能稍微往左站一站?
Local tour guide: Uh, why don't you move just a little bit more to your left?
迈克:你到底想干什么……
Mike: Before I knew what happened...
本地导游:听我的,稍微往左靠一点.
Local tour guide: A little bit more.
迈克:她同意和我一起游览全岛.
Mike: She agreed to give me a private tour of the island.
本地导游:站齐了.很好【日语】
Local tour guide: More.Perfect.[Japanese]
迈克:可就在今天下午,我去被困在这条浴缸似的破船之上,
Mike: This afternoon.As in today, but no I'm out here on this stupid tub.
T-U-B! T-U-B.
开萝尔:活该你倒霉.你不是吹牛可以说服爸妈让我呆在家里吗?现在可好!!
Carol: Serves you right.You were gonna get me out of this trip, remember?
迈克:老爸,咱俩能谈谈吗?
Mike: Uh, Dad.You got a sec?
杰森:等等,别着急!我正在和旅行社商谈具体事情呢!!
Jason: Hold on.Hold on.I'm talking to the travel agent.
本:迈克,废话少说!
Ben: Get out of the shot, Mike!
杰森:行!这样可以,我们没意见.
Jason: Yea.No, no.We can fly coach.
迈克:嗯,妈妈,我能跟您谈谈吗?
Mike: Uh, Mom, mom.You got a sec?
麦琪:当然了,儿子,什么事?
Maggie: Uh, sure, Mike.
迈克:嗯,
Mike: Yea, well, see,
妹妹她不想参加这次家庭渡假,她想跟鲍比呆在一起,
Carol wants to blow off this whole family vacation thing so she can hang
您同意吗?
out with Bobby while we're gone.What do you say?
麦琪:当然不行!
Maggie: Absolutely not.
迈克:看到了吧!我试过了,但妈妈不许!
Mike: Eh, I tried.
开萝尔:这也算?!鲍比,恐怕我不能跟你一起分享你的假期了!
Carol: What?!Bobby, I'll miss you every single second we're gone.
鲍比:我会想你的.记着,
Bobby: I'm really going to miss you, too.
每天六点我会准时打电话给你.等等,
And remember, I'll call you every day at six o'clock. Wait a minute.
六点是你那边的时间,我这边是……
That's six o'clock your time.My time will be, uh...
开萝尔:困在这么一条臭船里,
Carol: So here I am stuck on this stinking excuse for a boat.
连他的电话也接不到.
I can't even get his call.
他准以为我碰到帅哥立马见异思迁,
He's gonna think I met some gorgeous hunk who swept me off my feet and
把他给忘得一干二净.
that I'm playing around on him.
迈克:他怎么会这么想呢?
Mike: Why would he think that?
麦琪:省省吧,孩子们!别老实一脸不高兴,
Maggie: Come on, you guys.Lose the long faces.I'm trying to cheer your Dad up.
我去给你爸爸宽宽心,你们也打起精神,明白吗?
You could help, you know.
开萝尔:我还觉得难受呢,起码你能跟他一起去岸边钓鱼,
Carol: I can't believe that while I've got to get to shore,
而我呢?!
you're gonna sit here and fish!
麦琪:行了,我要去洗澡,你们啊好自为之吧!!
Maggie: Well, I have to go to the bathroom, but we don't always get our way.
迈克:妈妈,别这样!
Mike: Oh, come on, Mom.It's easy for you.
说得容易,你当然没要紧事要做了,而我们都有事要去忙!
I mean what else do you have to do other than float around out here?
麦琪:孩子话!!你们以为我就容易了,
Maggie: What else?You kids have no idea what I've gone through,
为了让你爸爸能高高兴兴地度这个假,
what I'm going through, to make this trip the best vacation ever for your dad.
我做的牺牲你们知道吗.
Sure I had vacation time coming.Sure I wanted time with my family.
这一起都不是为了一家人能快快乐乐地呆在一起.有人眼红我这个差事,
But with hotshot new reporter after my job,
我一走开,她可不会放过这个千载难逢的好机会.
this was the worst possible time to leave.Carine Dubois.Ha!
凯琳·迪布埃斯这个女人最不是个东西.
Fake name if I ever heard one.
苏珊:麦琪!你作的那篇关于核电的系列报道,
Susan: Maggie!I am getting great reaction to part one of the nuclear power
读者反响很大,我们想继续进行跟踪报道.你什么时候能完成下一份报道?
series.When can you have part two?
麦琪:嗯,苏珊,
Maggie: Well, Susan, the thing is,
事情是这样的,我打算跟家人一起去毛利岛渡假,所以……
is that I am going with my family to Maui and...
苏珊:这样啊?
Susan: Oh?
麦琪:我会很快回来的……
Maggie: But I'll be back in...
苏珊:没事,你忙你的,这件事交给凯琳就行了.
Susan: Well, that's ok, I'll put Carine on it.
麦琪:凯琳?
Maggie: Carine?
苏珊:把你的任务全部交由她来处理.祝你旅途愉快.
Susan: Give her all your research.Have a good trip.
麦琪:但这是我发起的系列报道!!
Maggie: This is my series!
苏珊:过得开心!记得给我明信片!
Susan: Have fun!Send me a postcard.
麦琪:没问题!我一定会的!
Maggie: I'll do it!I'll do it!
你们也知道,自从来到这以后,
You know, from the day we got here,
我可一天也没闲着!
I haven't exactly been on a full time vacation.
你爸爸休息后,我还得继续我的工作.
When I went to bed with your father, the real work began.
开萝尔:你说什么??
Carol: What are you saying?
麦琪:可别让你爸爸听到!!孩子,
Maggie: Just stay with me, Carol.Oh, honey, I couldn't disappoint your dad.
我既不能让你爸爸不开心,也不能放弃自己的工作.
But I couldn't disappoint myself, either.
所以,千万不能让他知道此事,
So, I figured what he didn't know couldn't hurt him.
他肯定会为此而难受.
At night, when everyone else was sleeping,
等到夜里你爸爸睡着后,我就溜进卫生间写新闻稿.
I'd work on my story in the bathroom.
但若是你爸爸突然醒来,我就对他说水土不服--腹泻.
If your dad woke up, I could always use my old standby excuse.Diarrhea.
杰森:真的??
Jason: Oh, really?
麦琪:啊!亲爱的,我只是……
Maggie: Oh, honey, I...
杰森:噢!原来如此!
Jason: Oh, no, no, no.That's alright.No, no.
我终于明白为什么你总显得疲惫不堪了!!
That explains why you've been too tired to...socialize.
本:嘿,爸爸!把我们钓来的鱼给妈妈瞧瞧??
Ben: Hey, Dad!Aren't you going to show Mom the fish you caught?
杰森:当然不想!这没人愿意看我们钓来的鱼.
Jason: Absolutely not.No one gets to see my fish.
麦琪:亲爱的,请听我解释.
Maggie: Oh, honey, I can explain.
杰森:不用解释!
Jason: No, no.Don't say a word.I understand, I surrender.
我能理解你的苦衷,
I surrender to all of you.
我明白,
I was wrong to think that a family vacation might be a good idea.'
我知道你们的难处,我本来想全家人一起出来度假是个好主意,
Cause you've all got other things to do.
可没想到结果却是如此,
More important things than spending a little time with your loved ones.
原来你们都有别的事情要忙,
That's alright, forget it.Forget it.Let's be honest, this trip is over.
而且远比家里人在一起度假要重要.
Never mind.
迈克:嘿,老爸!那个是活塞吗?
Mike: Hey, Dad.Is that a spark plug?
杰森:得了吧,马克.
Jason: Forget it, Mike.
本:爸爸,你把镜头挡住了,我怎么拍录像呢?
Ben: Hey, Dad, I can't film it if you're standing on it.
麦琪:杰森,
Maggie: Jason, does that spark plug have anything to do with the fact
这活塞和我们被困水上有无关联?
that we're lying dead in the water?
迈克:当然有了,妈妈!
Mike: Yes, it does!
杰森:我算明白了,迈克现在不知在想什么呢,
Jason: Ok, you know,
开萝尔因为见不到男友而怏怏不乐,麦琪你也人在心不在?
with Mike running off all the time and Carol sulking and Maggie you have
是的,是的,
been preoccupied.Yes, yes, yes.
是的,
Well, I knew that if we could just spend a little...
我是说要是有谁,有谁逼着大家一起来度假的话,
if we were forced to spend some time together that fundamentally we all
当然了,基本上要愿意在一起的.
wanted to be together.
我想大家准会很高兴的,因为我觉得……
And I know you're gonna get a kick out of this because I just...
麦琪:杰森,看到活塞没?
Maggie: Jason.The spark plug.
杰森:什么活塞不活塞的?
Jason: What spark plug?
本:各位,我已拍到了整个渡假中最为精彩的录像了,要不要看看?
Ben: Hey, you guys, just wait until you see the neat stuff I videotaped!
大家:别闹了,本!!
Everybody: Shut up, Ben.
Carol: S-E-A-V-E-R.Are you sure there aren't any messages?Well
I'm sorry, too!Bobby probably called and when I wasn't here, he was so angry
he couldn't leave a message
杰森:啊哈!吃过晚饭一切就都好了.
Jason: Aw, well you'll feel better after your dinner.Come on!
现在去看看毛利岛的日落吧,肯定很神奇美妙.
We'll catch the wonder and the magic of a Maui sunset.
开萝尔:我要等电话,爸爸,还是你去吧!!
Carol: I can't leave this telephone, Dad.Are you crazy?
杰森:这都是我的错吗?麦琪!!
Jason: What was I thinking?Maggie!
麦琪:我肚子也很饿,
Maggie: I would eat Jason,
但是我得赶稿件,
but I have a deadline but I wasted so much time bobbing aimlessly about
困在海上浪费了不少时间.
in the ocean.
杰森:迈克,那你呢?!
Jason: Uh-huh.Mike!
本:爸爸,哥哥早就溜之大吉了.可能躲远了.
Ben: Oh, he's gone again.Maybe this time for good.
杰森:这下可能就剩咱爷俩喽!
Jason: Well, alright, then that leaves you and me, Ben.
本:爸爸,我已经吃过晚饭了!
Ben: My dinner's taken care of.
杰森:不会吧?!
Jason: What?
本:他们这儿有一种很好的服务,就是肚子饿得时候,
Ben: Well, see, there's this really neat thing here.
只要拿起电话,
You just pick up the phone, tell them what you want,
告诉他们你想吃什么,他们立刻就会送到房间里.
and they bring it right to your room.
杰森:客房服务?
Jason: Room service?
本:好像就是!甚至连门都不用出!
Ben: That's it!And you can eat it in your underwear!
杰森:孩子,
Jason: Come on, Ben.
渡假就是为了出来到处逛逛,这样才能交结朋友,
The whole point of a vacation is to get out, so you can see things,
才能体会大自然的一切.
and you can meet people, and you'll have a good...
哈德利:你好啊,本!干什么呢?
Hadley: Hey, Ben!Hey, how's it going?
本:你好,哈德利!
Ben: Hi Hadley.
杰森:那我就自个去了!
Jason: I'll be in the restaurant.Alone.Ok, bye!
哈德利:再见,班尼!
Hadley: Bye!Here you go, Benny.
本:想和我一起去吃饭吗?
Ben: Wanna eat with me?
哈德利:不想!你们是纳粹吗?
Hadley: Naw, I can't do it.Nazi's?
开萝尔:当然不是,我们来自纽约.
Carol: No, we're New Yorkers.
哈德利:不是?瞧瞧你们看的书,
Hadley: No, your book.
我第一次看到游客读本书.对了,
This may be the first time I've ever seen a guest reading that.
奥地利总统好像也读过.
Oh, wait, there was another time Kirk Waldheim stayed here once.
别担心,开个历史玩笑而已.
It's a little history joke.
开萝尔:有意思!
Carol: That's funny!
哈德利:事实上,秋天我就要去耶鲁大学攻读历史了!
Hadley: Actually, history's going to be major at Yale in the fall.
开萝尔:耶鲁大学?我也很喜欢历史.
Carol: Yale, huh?Well, I love history, too.
哈德利:没开玩笑吧?
Hadley: No kidding?
开萝尔:当然不是!
Carol: Yea!
哈德利:义和团暴动?中世纪?
Hadley: The Boxer rebellion?The Dark Ages?
开萝尔:宗教色彩很浓!
Carol: The Inquisition!
哈德利:真是有趣!!
Hadley: That's fun stuff!
开萝尔:那当然!
Carol: I'll say!
哈德利:这样吧,明天我休息,我们能够一起探讨一下关于欧洲瘟疫流行时期的历史吗?
Hadley: Well, listen, um, tomorrow's my day off, you wouldn't want to get together and have a little chat about the Black Plague of Europe would you?
本:不行,她已经约了别人.
Ben: She can't, she's going with some guy.
开萝尔:乱讲!
Carol: Shut up, Ben.
玛利亚:嗨,迈克!
Malia: Aloha, Mike.
迈克:送花时是不是要吻一下??
Mike: Uh, don't these things usually come with a kiss?
玛利亚:嗯哼!你什么都没带就出来混?
Malia: Yea.Did you remember to bring your trunks?
迈克:是啊,只想着你了,别的什么都忘了!
Mike: Hey, I haven't been able to think about anything else.
(唱歌)
(sing)
玛利亚:你喜欢这里吗?
Malia: You're gonna love this!Well, what do you think?
迈克:嗨,你打算带我去哪?
Mike: Uh, look, where you taking me?
玛利亚:定会让你开心的,走吧,快点!!
Malia: Some place neat.Come on!Come on.
迈克:嗯!!你看这不是坟地吗!
Mike: Uh, you know, there's dead people here.
玛利亚:当然!我曾祖父,曾祖父的父亲,还有我姑奶奶劳姬…..
Malia: Sure, my great grandfather, his father, and my great aunt Loki...
迈克:嗯,我明白,
Mike: Yeah, well, you know I'm sure they're very nice people.
他们生前都是好人,行端品直.
Uh, polite, well behaved.
玛利亚:别说话,跟着我就行了.
Malia: Just follow me.
迈克:我们到底要去哪??
Mike: Look, where are we going?
玛利亚:升天啊!
迈克:你这话是啥意思?!!
00:22:57,600
Malia: To heaven. Mike: Exactly how do you mean that?